A Finding Aid to the Julia P. Herzberg Papers, 1977-2018, bulk 1987-2011, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Julia P. Herzberg papers
1977-2018
bulk 1987-2011
Archives of American Art
Herzberg, Julia P.
AAA.herzjuli
Archival Resource Key
8.4 Linear feet
18.4 Gigabytes
The papers of curator and art historian Julia P. Herzberg measure 8.4 linear feet and 18.4 Gigabytes and date from 1977-2018. Included are Herzberg's files on exhibitions and artists containing correspondence, printed material, interview transcripts, and notes and drafts by Herzberg. Artists include Wilfredo Lam, Doris Salcedo, Ana Mendieta, and Jorge Tacla, and Catalina Parra, among others.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 4 series.
Series 1: Writing Projects, 1998-2018 (1.1 linear feet: Box 3, 5, 6, 8; 0.446 Gigabytes: ER0001-ER0004)
Series 2: Artist Files, 1977-2018 (5.4 linear feet: Box 1-8; 4.8 Gigabytes: ER0005-ER0012, ER0028)
Series 3: Exhibition Files, 1990-2017 (1.6 linear feet: Box 1, 3, 8-9; 13.1 Gigabytes: ER0013-ER0027, ER0029)
Series 4: Professional Files, 2003-2014 (0.3 linear feet: Box 1, 3, 8)
Biographical / Historical
Julia P. Herzberg (194?-) is a curator, art historian and editor in New York, N.Y. Herzberg specializes in Latin American contemporary art. Her work is centered on the research, scholarship, and cultural production of artistic practices within interdisciplinary global contexts. She has curated numerous exhibitions throughout North America and Latin America.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Researchers interested in accessing audiovisual recordings and born-digital records in this collection must use access copies. Contact References Services for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Julia P. Herzberg in 2018 and 2021.
Scope and Contents
The papers of curator and art historian Julia P. Herzberg measure 8.4 linear feet and 18.4 Gigabytes and date from 1977-2018. Included are Herzberg's files on exhibitions and artists containing correspondence, printed material, interview transcripts, and notes and drafts by Herzberg. Artists include Wilfredo Lam, Doris Salcedo, Ana Mendieta, Catalina Parra, and Jorge Tacla among others.
Materials in this collection document Herzberg's career as a curator, art historian, and editor, and consist of Herzberg's curatorial and project files related to artists, exhibitions, writing, and other professional projects. Included are draft lectures, essays, and articles; bibliographies; clippings; exhibition catalogs, announcements, flyers, and posters; correspondence with artists and curators; notes; clippings; pamphlets; artist biographies and CVs; exhibition planning documents including proposals, wall texts, working checklists, and diagrams; interview transcripts; photographs, slides, and negatives; and press releases. Some of Herzberg's files, including photographs and writings, are in born-digital format.
Art historians -- New York (State) -- New York; Art, Latin American; Art museum curators -- New York (State) -- New York; Interviews; Women art historians; Alfonzo, Carlos, 1950-1991; Kaikkonen, Kaarina, 1952-; Katz, Leandro, 1938-; Lam, Wifredo; Rabinovich, Raquel, 1929-; Parra, Catalina; Fernández, Magdalena, 1964-; Weiss, Monika, 1964-
- Writing Projects, 1998-2018; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 1.1 Linear feet Box 3, 5, 6, 8; 0.446 Gigabytes ER0001-ER0004
  Arrangement
  The box and folder order are arranged in the original order created by the donor, following the inventory in box 8 folders 22-23.
  Scope and Contents
  Writing projects reflect the various types of curatorial and editorial writing Herzberg produced including reviews, articles, lectures, talks, panel discussions and essays. Materials include draft lectures, essays, and articles; notes; reviews; exhibition catalogs; photographic material; and correspondence, some in digital formats. Herzberg wrote numerous articles and catalog essays throughout her long career, and sat on panels and gave lectures related to Latin American contemporary art and artists. Projects of note include her work as an essayist for Pacific Standard Time: LA/LA and the Times Square Alliance.
  - Lecture on "The Decade Show" for the Asian American Studies Conference, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Essay, "Four Ways, A Room of Her Own", 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lecture, "Artistas latinoamericanos: Reflections on Their Jewish Identity", 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Article, "Departures from Common Things: Emerging Paths, Chile", 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lecture, "Spirituality and Divinity in Contemporary Latino Art and Latin American Art", 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Article, "Ana Mendieta and Carl Andre: Duet of Leaf and Stone", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lecture, "Portraiture, Performance, and Body Art: Connections and Resonances", 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Lecture, "Effervescent Moments in Modern and Contemporary Argentine Art History", 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Time Square Alliance Essay, "Arrechea and Maldonado in the Heart of Times Square", 2010-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Article, "El Museo del Barrio: Celebrating 40 Years", 2009-2010; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records; see ER0001. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "El Museo del Barrio: Celebrating 40 Years", Digital Photographs and Documents, 2009; Archival Resource Key; 0.02 Gigabytes 7 computer files (Folder ER0001)
  - Essays, Pacific Standard Time: LA/LA, 2016-2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
  - Gory Project, Correspondence, 2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Met Breuer, Exhibitions, 2015-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Doris Salcedo, Correspondence and Drafts, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Nossa Ameria de Memoria de Latina America 2012, 2011-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - "Arte Brasileiros Leonora and Raquel Rabinovich", 2010-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Emilio Chapela Art al Dia Intermacional, Articles and Correspondence, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Labor, Research, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Yoan Capote Art Review, 2004-2010, undated; Archival Resource Key; Include born-digital records; see ER0002-ER0003. (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Yoan Capote, Digital Photographs and Documents, 2005-2009; Archival Resource Key; 0.41 Gigabytes 112 computer files (Folder ER0002)
  - Yoan Capote, Digital Slideshow, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.012 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER0003)
  - Juan Manuel Echavarria, Correspondence, 2006-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Arte! Brasileiros, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Leandro Katz in Conversation with Julia P. Herzberg, 2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Leandro Katz - Review, Arte al Dia International, 2009-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - El Museo del Barrio: Celebrating 40 Years, Articles, 2009; Archival Resource Key; Inccludes born-digital records; see ER0004. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - El Museo del Barrio, 40th Anniversary Press Kit, Digital Document, 2009; Archival Resource Key; 0.004 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER0004)
  - Lotty Rosenfield, Correspondence, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Wall Text, Captions From EMDB, Arte =/= Vida, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Carlos Alfonzo, Christies, Correspondence, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Ana Mendieta, Articles and Correspondence, 2000-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Lectures, 1998-2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Artist Files, 1977-2018; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 5.4 Linear feet Box 1-8; 4.8 Gigabytes ER0005-ER0012, ER0028
  The bulk of the collection, artist files document Herzberg's work with artists through interview transcripts; correspondence; clippings; notes; exhibition catalogs, announcements, and working checklists; draft essays; articles; photographs, slides, and negatives depicting works of art; press releases; artist biographies and CVs. This material often reflects Herzberg's close relationships with artists through numerous curatorial projects found in the artist files. Of note are an interview with Carmen Herrera, an illustrated letter from Luis Benedict, and a holiday card from Ernest Pujol. Some of the materials are in digital formats.
  - Carlos Alfonzo, Exhibition Research, 1988-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Carlos Alfonzo, Research, 1987-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22-25)
  - Carlos Alfonzo, Exhibitions, 1984-2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Raquel Rabinovich, Exhibitions, 1981-1995, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4-5, 7)
  - Raquel Rabinovich, Hudson River Project, 2005-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Raquel Rabinovich, Research, 1986-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8, 11)
  - Raquel Rabinovich, "River Library" Catalog, 2001-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Raquel Rabinovich, Lecture Drafts, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Nela Ochoa, Exhibitions, 2001-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13-16)
  - Nela Ochoa, Frost Museum Catalog, 2008-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Natalia Arias, Essays, 2008-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Natalia Arias, Exhibitions, 2006-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Anake Asseff, Research, 2010; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER0005. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Anake Asseff, Digital Video Recordings and Presentations, 2006-2010; Archival Resource Key; 1.82 Gigabytes 6 computer files (Folder ER0005)
  - Bibi Calderaro, Research, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Luis Cruz Azeceta, Research, 1980-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Jose Bedia, Research, 1982-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Luis Benedit, Letter, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Hans Breder, Exhibitions, 2001, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Sandra Bermudez, Exhibitions, 2000-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Marcelo Bonevardi, Article, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Tania Brugera, Essays, 2005-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Luis Camnitzer, Exhibitions, 2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Maria Magdalena Campos Pons, Research, 1985-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Maria Magdalena Campos Pons, Research, 1990-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Pablo Cano, Exhibitions, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Josely Carvalho, Research, 1982-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4-5, 7)
  - Josely Carvalho, Essays, 1986-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6, 8)
  - Liset Castillo, Exhibitions, 1986-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Emelio Chapela, Interview Transcripts, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Marta Chilindron, Research, 1997-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Marta Chilindron Multimedia Bio, Digital Documents, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 70 computer files (Folder ER0006)
  - Claudio Correa, Research, 2004-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Magdalena Correa, 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Maximo Corvalan-Pinchera, Essays, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Eduardo Costa, Lectures, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Arturo Cuena, Essays, 1993, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Arturo Cuena, Research, 1986-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
  - Jaime Davidovich, Exhibitions, 1986-2018; Archival Resource Key; Include born-digital records; see ER0007. (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
  - Jewish Museum Proposal, Digital Photographs, 2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER0007)
  - Jack Delano, Exhibition Poster, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Mauricio Dias and Walter Riedweg, Essays, 2004-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Juan Douney, Correspondence, 2005, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Leandro Erlich, Exhibitions, 1999-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Hiroshi Watanabe, Exhibitions, 2001-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Paz Errazuriz, Research, 1994-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Teresita Fernandez, Research, 2006-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Juan Gonzalez, Research, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Maria Elena Gonzalez, Exhibitions, 1997-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Quisqueya Henriquez, Articles and Exhibitions, 2000-2006; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER0008. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Quisqueya Henriquez, Digital Photographs, Video Recordings, and Presentations, Archival Resource Key; 1.63 Gigabytes 30 computer files (Folder ER0008)
  - Carmen Herrera, Correspondence and Research, 2005-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Carmen Herrera: 5 Degrees of Freedom, Digital Video Recording, 2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.662 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER0009)
  - Luis Jimenez, Notes, 1988-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Roberto Juarez, Press Release, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Wilfredo Lam, Correspondence and Exhibitions, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Wilfredo Lam, Exhibitions, 2015-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Wilfredo Lam, Research, 2010-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
  - Wilfredo Lam, Correspondence and Research, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Wilfredo Lam, Essays, 1992-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
  - Wilfredo Lam, Articles, 1987-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Teresita Fernandez, Essays and Research, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Doris Salcedo, Research, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Francisca Sutil, Correspondence, 2013; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records; see ER0010. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Francisca Sutil Artwork, Digital Photographs, 2013; Archival Resource Key; 0.018 Gigabytes 23 computer files (Folder ER0010)
  - Charles Juhasz Alvarado, Exhibitions, 1998-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Kaarina Kaikkonen, Exhibitions, 2003-2006; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records; see ER0011. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Kaarina Kaikkonen Artwork, Digital Photographs, 2003; Archival Resource Key; 0.003 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER0011)
  - Kaarina Kaikkonen, Correspondence, 2011-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Kaarina Kaikkonen, Correspondence, Essays, and Exhibitions, 2005-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Kaarina Kaikkonen, Exhibitions, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Kaarina Kaikkonen, Essays, 2012-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Leandro Katz, Exhibitions and Research, 1975-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Leandro Katz, Articles and Research, 1991-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Leandro Katz, Articles and Correspondence, 1996-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Leandro Katz, Exhibition Catalogue, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Guillermo Kuitca, Articles and Research, 1991-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Arturo Lindsay, Articles and Correspondence, 1992-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Esteban Lisa, Research, 1983-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
  - Marco Maggi, Research, 2007-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Anna Maria Maiolina, Exhibition, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Leopoldo Maler, Exhibitions, 2008-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Luis Mallo, Exhibitions, 2005-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Maria Martinez-Canas, Correspondence and Exhibitions, 1999-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Ana Mendieta, Essays and Lectures, 1999-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Amalia Mesa-Bains, Exhibitions and Research, 1993-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Marta Minujin, Articles and Research, 1996-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Franco Mondini-Ruiz, Exhibitions, 1996-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Franco Mondini-Ruiz, Research, 1996-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - Mondongo, List of Artworks, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Carlos Motta, Research, 2008-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Dario Oleaga, Exhibitions, 2000-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Pepon Osorio, Exhibitions and Research, 1994-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Pepon Osorio, Articles, 1997-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
  - Catalina Parra, Articles, 1971-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Catalina Parra, Essays, 2000-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Marta Maria Perez Bravo, Exhibitions, 1988-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Cesar Paternosto, Research, 1981-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Ernesto Pujol, Exhibitions, 1995-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18, 20-22)
  - Ernesto Pujol, Drafts and Exhibitions, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Maura Reiley, Article, 2017-2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Juan Sanchez, Exhibitions, 1982-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Juan Sanchez, Correspondence and Exhibitions, 1989-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Bastienne Schmidt, Exhibitions, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Antonio Segui, Essay, 1977-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Regina Silveira, Exhibitions, 1983-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Grete Stern, Research, 1988-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Grete Stern, Exhibitions, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Jorge Tacla, Research and Drafts, 2007-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Ana Tiscornia, Exhibitions, 1996-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Ruebn Torres, Llora Arte al Dia, 1997-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Cesar Trasobares, Research, 1979-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Gladys Triana, Correspondence, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Gabriel Valansi, Research, 2005; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER0012. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Gabriel Valansi, Digital Video Recordings and Documents, 2002-2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 7 computer files (Folder ER0012)
  - Eugenia Vargas, Research, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Manuela Viera-Gallo, Research, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Cecilia Vicuna, Research, 1982-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Lucia Warck Meister, Research, 1999-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Ximena Zamosa, Research, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Monika Weiss, Biographies, circa 2007-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Monika Weiss, Correspondence, circa 2013, 2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Monika Weiss, Correspondence, U.S. Embassy in Warsaw, circa 2009, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Monika Weiss, Correspondence, Tenure Recommendation, Washington University St. Louis, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Monika Weiss, Artist Statements, circa 2005-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Monika Weiss, Artwork Descriptions Keimani, circa 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Monika Weiss, Interview with Julia Herzberg for Poza Exhibition Catalog, Real Art Ways (Oct 2005-Jan. 2006), circa 2005-2006; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER0028. (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Monika Weiss, Interview with Julia Herzberg, Digital Video Recording, 2006; Archival Resource Key; 0.646 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER0028)
  - Monika Weiss, Essay "M.W.: Language of Lament: History, Memory and the Body", circa 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Monika Weiss, Exhibitions, circa 2005-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Monika Weiss, Articles by Others, circa 2005-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Exhibition Files, 1990-2017; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 1.6 Linear feet Box 1, 3, 8-9; 13.1 Gigabytes ER0013-ER0027, ER0029
  Exhibition files document Herzberg's curatorial work from the 1980s through the 2010s. Materials include photographs, slides, and negatives depicting exhibition openings, installations, and works of art; working checklists; floor plans; correspondence; press releases; bibliographies; clippings; reviews; draft essays and articles; research notes; printouts; wall text; proposals; and agreements. Exhibitions of note include the 8th, 9th, 10th, and 11th Havana Biennials; "The Decade Show: Frameworks of Identity in the 1980s;" and "Chilean Women Artists, Feminism and Dissidence." Some of the materials are in digital formats.
  - "8th Havana Biennial" (2000), 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "8th Havana Biennial" (2003), 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "9th Havana Biennial" (2006), 2006-2007; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER0013-ER0014. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Claudia del Fierro Identica And Other Works, Digital Video Recording, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key; 3.34 Gigabytes (Folder ER0013)
  - Sze Tsung Leong, Digital Photographs and Documents, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.08 Gigabytes 134 computer files (Folder ER0014)
  - "10th Havana Biennial" (2009), 2008-2009; Archival Resource Key; Include born-digital records, see ER0015-ER0017. (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
  - Various Artists, Digital Photographs and Documents, 2009; Archival Resource Key; 0.032 Gigabytes 12 computer files (Folder ER0015)
  - Lluís Barba, Digital Photographs and Documents, 2007, 2009; Archival Resource Key; 0.085 Gigabytes 114 computer files (Folder ER0016)
  - Punkasila, Acronym Wars, Digital Audio Recordings, 2006; Archival Resource Key; 0.307 Gigabytes 18 computer files (Folder ER0017)
  - "11th Havana Biennial" (2012), 2014, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Cuenca Biennial" (2009), 2008-2009; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER0018. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Various Artists, Digital Photographs and Documents, 2002-2009; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Gigabytes 857 computer files (Folder ER0018)
  - "Pinta NY Art Fair" (2013), 2013-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ARTBO, International Art Fair of Bogota, 2011-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "The Decade Show: Frameworks of Identity in the 1980s" (1990), 1990, 2001-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Wilfredo Lam and his Contemporaries, 1938-1952" (1992), Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Recovering Histories: Aspects of Contemporary Art in Chile Since 1982" (1993), circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)